# Amir Yazdani

Nttps://amir-yazdani.github.io/

in amir-yazdani-robotics





### **SUMMARY**

I am a researcher and a PhD candidate in robotics with the goal of improving human-robot interaction (HRI) through developing new algorithms for robot perception and planning. My current research includes probabilistic perception and planning in HRI and covers human state estimation, ergonomics & safety optimization, teleoperation, risk-aware motion & manipulation planning, and inverse reinforcement learning.

I am also interested in online and reactive motion planning for human-robot & robot-robot co-existence and spent a summer internship at the OMRON Research Center of America (ORCA) on this topic.

#### **SKILLS**

HRI Artificial Intelligence **Machine Learning Planning Software Hardware** 

Ergonomics and safety in HRI, Posture Estimation, Human factors, Motion Analysis State estimation & SLAM, (PO)MDP, HMM, Bayes filters, Smoothing, Prediction PyTorch, sklearn, skorch, Tensorflow, Keras

Optimal & search-based motion planning, MPC, A\*, RRT, PRM, MIQP, Convex Opt. Python, C++, ROS, Gazebo, OpenCV, OpenPose, KDL, DART, MATLAB Simulink, Gurobi Robots (Baxter, KUKA iiwa & Ibr4, Omron Cobra & Viper, iRobot Create 2), Haptic robots (Quanser HD<sup>2</sup>, Phantom Omni, Phantom Premium, Novint Falcon), Sensors (RGB cameras, Kinect Azure & v2, Laser range finders, Motion capture)

#### **EXPERIENCES**

# **Reactive Trajectory Planning for Fixed Robots**

Robotics Research Intern, Supervisors: John Drinkard

Omron Research Center of America, San Ramon, CA Summer 2019

· I researched on reactive trajectory planning for industrial robots and successfully implemented a reactive trajectory planning approach on a robot-robot co-existence scenario.

Human-Robot Interaction / Robot Perception LL4MA Lab & Ergonomics and Safety Lab, University of Utah Research Assistant, Supervisors: Tucker Hermans, Andrew Merryweather, Jake Abbott lan. 2016 - present

- I am working on 3D posture estimation of infants from single-view videos and utilizing inverse reinforcement learning to understand the cruising motion skills of infants to be transferred into robots. This project is funded by DARPA and includes collaboration with psychologists from NYU and AI scientists from OSU.
- I am developing a framework for postural optimization in teleoperation w.r.t. teleoperation task type including both derivative-based and derivative-free optimizations
- I developed a full teleportation simulation environment in Gazebo including leader and follower robots as well as the human teleopereator. The teleoperator model includes a receding horizon online motion planner that performs the teleoperation based on observing the motion of the follower robot, as well as applying postural correction.
- I learned a neural network model for RULA risk assessment tool using skorch with 95% accuracy to be used in our derivative-based postural optimization approach.
- I developed a new algorithm for probabilistic human posture estimation in teleoperation that infers posture solely from the trajectory of the leader robot without any vision system. Comparing to a MoCap system, our approach has almost 5 deg of deviation in joint angles. The risk assessment using the estimated posture from our approach results in the same interpretation in RULA score for more than 84.37% of the trials a human-subject study, when compared to the risk assessment for the posture from a MoCap system.
- · I collaborated on developing a probabilistic risk-aware decision making for a patient assistant mobile robot that leverages the predictive models of patient motion, and manipulation planning to minimize the risk of patient falls in the hospital rooms, by providing supporting objects during ambulation.

- I developed a haptic guidance algorithm including virtual fixtures and synthetic fixtures to guide the user through a maze using a Quanser HD2 haptic robot
- I implemented safety parameters into an optimal motion planning algorithm using MPC for serial robots to improve the safety and productivity of the task in a shared autonomy
- I collaborated on developing a mobile manipulation planning algorithm based on MPC and convex optimization to push/pull legged objects. The results are published in IROS 2018 and IJRR.
- I developed an algorithm for push planning of objects by mobile robots using a mixture of A\* and RRT-connect and the simulation results prove the performance of our approach.
- I collaborated in implementing and benchmarking several optimization techniques for solving inverse kinematics and trajectory optimization of robot arms as a optimization mini course
- I collaborated on implementing visual SLAM using RGB-D and monocular cameras on a mobile robot.
- I collaborated on a project to control an under-actuated wearable arm-swing rehabilitator for gait training.
- I collaborated in designing and developing an under-actuated robotic hand for grasping legged objects with various leg diameters.

# **Motion Planning / Parallel Robots**

TaarLab, The University of Tehran, Tehran, Iran

Research Associate, Supervisor: Mehdi Tale Masouleh, Mohammad Bagher Menhaj

Dec. 2011 - Dec. 2015

- I developed a fault-tolerant optimal collision-free motion planning algorithm based on convex optimization and MPC for robot arms and implemented on a developed 4-DOF planar & redundant serial robot.
- I collaborated on developing an optimal collision-free motion generation algorithm based on convex optimization and MPC and implementing it on various mobile, serial and parallel robots.
- I collaborated on developing PGNGN, a neural gas network algorithm for finding the singularity-free workspace of planar parallel robots.
- I designed and developed several parallel robots including a 6-DOF pneumatic Gouph-Stewart, a 4-DOF Quattrobased, a 3-DOF and a 2-DOF spherical, and a 3-DOF Cartesian parallel robot and collaborated in dynamic modeling and computed torque control of them.

# **Haptic Robots / Driving Simulators** Virtual Reality Lab, K. N. Toosi University of Technology, Tehran, Iran Research Assistant & Lab manager, Supervisor: Ali Nahvi July 2008 - Sep. 2011

- I designed and developed VirSense, a 6-DOF haptic device with fixed-base actuators and 95% passive gravity compensation using linear springs.
- I designed a novel 4-DOF serial-parallel robot for real-size urban bus driving simulators and collaborated in development and kinematic analysis of the mechanism.

# **EDUCATION**

# University of Utah, Salt Lake City, UT

JAN 2016 - Present

PhD in Mechanical Engineering (Robotics Track), Thesis: "Haptic Posture Estimation and Guidance to Improve Ergonomics in Telemanipulation"

# AmirKabir University of Technology, Tehran, Iran

FEB 2013 - JUN 2015

MSc in Mechanical Engineering, Thesis: "Optimal Trajectory Planning and Fault-Tolerant Control of Redundant Planar Serial Manipulators"

#### K. N. Toosi University of Technology, Tehran, Iran

SEP 2005 - SEP 2010

BSc in Mechanical Engineering, Thesis: "Design and Development of VirSense: A Novel Haptic Device With Fixed-Base Actuators and Gravity Compensation"

#### RELATED PEER-REVIEWED PUBLICATIONS

I. **A.Yazdani**, R. SabbaghNovin, A. Merryweather, T. Hermans, "Postural Optimization for Ergonomically Intelligent Teleoperation Systems", Submitting to *Transaction on Robotics*.

- 2. **A.Yazdani**, R. SabbaghNovin, A. Merryweather, T. Hermans, "Is The Leader Robot an Adequate Sensor for Posture Estimation and Ergonomic Assessment of A Human Teleoperator?", Submitting to ACM Transaction of Human-Robot Interaction (THRI), Available on arXiv.
- 3. **A. Yazdani**, R. SabbaghNovin, "Posture Estimation and Optimization in Ergonomically Intelligent Teleoperation Systems", In Companion of the *HRI 2021*.
- 4. R. SabbaghNovin, **A. Yazdani**, A. Merryweather, T. Hermans, "Risk-Aware Decision Making in Service Robots to Minimize Risk of Patient Falls in Hospitals", Submitted to ICRA 2021.
- 5. R. SabbaghNovin, **A. Yazdani**, A. Merryweather, T. Hermans, "A model predictive approach for online mobile manipulation of nonholonomic objects using learned dynamics", *International Journal of Robotics Research (IJRR)*, 2020.
- 6. R. SabbaghNovin, **A. Yazdani**, T. Hermans, and A. Merryweather, "Dynamics model learning and manipulation planning for objects in hospitals using a patient assistant mobile (PAM) robot." *IROS 2018*, Madrid, Spain.
- 7. R. SabbaghNovin, M. Tale Masouleh, and **M. Yazdani**. "Optimal motion planning of redundant planar serial robots using a synergy-based approach of convex optimization, disjunctive programming and receding horizon." *Proceedings of the Institution of Mechanical Engineers, Part I: Journal of Systems and Control Engineering* 230, no. 3 (2016): 211-221.
- 8. R. SabbaghNovin, M. Tale Masouleh, **M. Yazdani** and B. Danaei. "Optimal motion planning of a 3-DOF decoupled parallel robot using convex optimization and receding horizon concept." *Modares Mechanical Engineering* (2015).
- 9. R. SabbaghNovin, A. Karimi, **M.Yazdani**, and M.Tale Masouleh. "Optimal motion planning for parallel robots via convex optimization and receding horizon." *Advanced Robotics*, 30, no. 17-18 (2016): 1145-1163.
- 10. **M.Yazdani**, R. SabbaghNovin, M. Tale Masouleh, M. Menhaj, and H. Abdi. "An experimental study on the failure tolerant control of a redundant planar serial manipulator via pseudo-inverse approach." *ICRoM* 2015, Tehran, Iran.
- 11. A. Mashayekhi, A. Nahvi, **M. Yazdani**, M. Mohammadi Moghadam, M. Arbabtafti, and M. Norouzi. "VirSense: a novel haptic device with fixed-base motors and a gravity compensation system." *Industrial Robot* (2014).
- 12. R. SabbaghNovin, M. Tale Masouleh, and **M.Yazdani**. "A new neural gas network approach for obtaining the singularity-free workspace of 3-DOF planar parallel manipulators.", *Proceedings of the Institution of Mechanical Engineers, Part C: Journal of Mechanical Engineering Science* (2016).
- M. ZamaniFekri, M. Zareei, M. Tale Masouleh, and M. Yazdani. "Optimal design and fabrication of a 4-DOF quattrotaar parallel robot with singularity-free workspace by ABC and PSO algorithms.", Modares Mechanical Engineering, (2016): Vol 16 No 6, 149-158.
- 14. **M.Yazdani**, M.Tale Masouleh, M. Hasanvand, I.Yahyapour, and M. Ghafouri Tabrizi. "Inverse dynamic problem of two parallel manipulators with identical limbs structures.", *Modares Mechanical Engineering*, Vol 15 No 13, 281-290 (2015).
- 15. A. Jaberi, A. Nahvi, M. Hasanvand, M.Tale-Masouleh, M. Arbabtafti, and **M. Yazdani**. "Design and kinematic analysis of a 4-DOF serial-parallel manipulator for a driving simulator." *International Journal of Robotics (Theory and Applications)* Vol.4, No. 3, 29-37 (2015).
- 16. E. Rostami Jame Bozorgi, I. Yahyapour, A. Karimi, M. Tale Masouleh, and **M. Yazdani**. "Design, development, dynamic analysis and control of a 2-DOF spherical parallel mechanism." *ICRoM* 2014, Tehran, Iran.
- 17. I.Yahyapour, M. Yazdani, M. Tale Masouleh, and M. Ghafouri Tabrizi. "Dynamic modeling and computed torque control of a 3-DOF spherical parallel manipulator." ICRoM 2014, Tehran, Iran.
- 18. R. SabbaghNovin, **M. Yazdani**, M.Tale Masouleh, and M. Menhaj. "Workspace determination of planar parallel robots via progressive growing neural gas network." *ICRoM 2014*, Tehran, Iran.
- 19. A. Jaberi, A. Nahvi, M. Hasanvand, M. Tale Masouleh, M. Arbabtafti, **M. Yazdani**, M. Lagha, M. Hemmatabadi, and S. Samiezadeh. "Design and kinematic analysis of a 4-DOF serial-parallel manipulator for urban bus driving simulator." *ICRoM 2013*, Tehran, Iran.
- 20. I. Yahyapour, M. Hasanvand, M. Tale Masouleh, **M. Yazdani**, and S. Tavakoli. "On the inverse dynamic problem of a 3-PRRR parallel manipulator, the Tripteron." *ICRoM* 2013, Tehran, Iran.

#### **PATENTS**

- 4-degree of freedom industrial-researching parallel robot with free singularity workspace, No.91977 issued by Iranian Organization of Patents Registration.
- Pneumatically Actuated 6-DoF Gough-Stewart Parallel Robot, No.446327 issued by Iranian Organization of Patents Registration.
- Design and Development of a Haptic Robot with Fixed-Based Actuators and Automatic Gravity Compensation,
  No.75817 issued by Iranian Organization of Patents Registration.
- Mechanism for Rapid Video Recording, No.78963 issued by Iranian Organization of Patents Registration. 2013

#### **AWARDS & HONORS**

IEEE/ACM Human-Robot Interaction Pioneer	2021
Dr. Paul Richard's Safe Workplace Scholarship by WCF Insurance	2017, 2018 & 2019
American Society of Safety Engineering Foundation Scholarship	2018, 2019
Graduate Student Travel Assistance award, Graduate School, The University of Utah	2018
Pilot Project Research Training (PPRT) Award from National Institute of Occupational	2016
Safety and Health (NIOSH), Award number: T420H008414-10	
ullet 1st place in Senior Demo league in Robocup IranOpen	2014

# **PEER REVIEW ACTIVITIES**

- SAGE: Journal of Systems and Control Engineering
- IEEE: RA-L, RSS, ICRA, IROS, Humanoinds, ICROM
- ACM: HRI
- ELSEVIER: Medicina
- MDPI: Sensors, Robotics, Applied Science, Technologies

#### **MEMBERSHIPS**

- Student member of IEEE
- Student member of Robotic & Automation Society (RAS)
- Student member of American Society of Safety Engineering (ASSE)